<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title/><link>https://wwymak.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 10:32:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wwymak.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spiced croissant buns</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-02-02-spiced-crossant-buns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 10:32:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-02-02-spiced-crossant-buns/</guid><description>| [ | | |
This is my first time making laminated bread&amp;ndash; the recipe goes along the lines of:
Mix ingredients (flour, yeast, butter, milk), first proof at room temp &amp;ndash; much like normal bread, except for the extra butter Chill in fridge for a few hours to firm up the flour Make butter block Laminate for 2 folds (with 1 hour in the fridge in between) Laminate final time with spiced butter (butter + sugar + mincepie filling) Bake I found it quite a bit trickier than laminated pastry&amp;ndash; the dough is a lot more elastic and hard to roll&amp;ndash; one is supposed to not overdo the rolling so you don&amp;rsquo;t squash the butter layers together, but as the dough is so still, I am convinced I did squashed some of the butter layers&amp;hellip; These buns also didn&amp;rsquo;t expand as much as the recipe indicates it should in the final proofing step.</description></item><item><title>Processing UK 2021 census open data with python tools</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2023-02-01-uk-population-census-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 18:54:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2023-02-01-uk-population-census-2021/</guid><description>Introduction The census provides a rich set of demographic information that could be useful for various data science tasks, such as geomarketing, house price analysis etc. With the results of the 2021 census being published recently, this notebook demonstrates how to manipulate this data with FOSS python tools to build a dataset that can be used for downstream tasks.
For this demo, I will be focusing on output areas (OA) of London:</description></item><item><title>Chinese Peanut Cookies</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-01-22-chinese-peanut-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 19:32:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-01-22-chinese-peanut-cookies/</guid><description>This year lunar new year is on the 22nd Jan, and as it nicely coincides with @sundayafternoonbakingclub penaut butter theme, I made these bite sized peanut cookies as they are popular as new year treats (or rather, more popular than usual&amp;ndash; I am fairly sure you can get them year round).
They are really easy to make as I took the shortcut and made them with PipandNut crunchy peanut butter &amp;ndash; you more or less peanut butter, oil, flour and sugar together, shape, and bake with an egg yolk egg wash.</description></item><item><title>Geo raster data parsing with rasterio</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2023-01-15-rasterio-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 18:54:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2023-01-15-rasterio-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>There are two main ways geospatial data are stored
rasters, where each &amp;lsquo;pixel&amp;rsquo; stores data values. This corresponds to files such as geotiffs. vectors, where information is stored more like a table form, and each row will have a &amp;lsquo;geometry&amp;rsquo; field which stores information that allows you to recreate a geographical feature, such as a point , a polygon etc. It might also store the coordinate reference system so you can correctly place the shapes on a map This set of notes corresponds to handling raster data.</description></item><item><title>Olive and sun dried tomato sourdough focaccia</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-01-06-olive-sundried-tomato-sourdough-focaccia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 18:32:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/bakery/2023-01-06-olive-sundried-tomato-sourdough-focaccia/</guid><description>Olive and sun dried tomato sourdough focaccia for this week’s @sundayafternoonbakingclub focaccia theme. The special sauce in this is my homemade chilli oil infused with chillis, Szechuan peppercorns, star anise and a few other spices. It gave it a nice bit of heat and also loads of flavour from all the other aromatics, and I definitely prefer this to plain olive oil.
I started off with my basic sourdough focaccia recipe but used a 50-50 mix of white and whole meal bread flour— and also accidentally ended up with a 100% hydration as I sifted out the bran from the wholemeal flour and forgot to compensate for it 😆</description></item><item><title>How to check if your deep learning library is actually using the GPU</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-13-tf-check-gpu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 20:54:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-13-tf-check-gpu/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve got a GPU on your system that you want to run your deep learning model on, you&amp;rsquo;d probably want to check that the library is able to access the GPU. Installation issues/ incorrect setups etc can mean that it&amp;rsquo;s actually inaccessible. I have googled far too many times &amp;lsquo;is tensorflow/pytorch accessing the GPU&amp;rsquo;, so putting this down here so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the same stackoverflow posts again and again 😅</description></item><item><title>How to count occurences in Bigquery Array/Repeated Fields</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-11-bigquery-tips-array-counts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-11-bigquery-tips-array-counts/</guid><description>In BigQuery, there is the concept of repeated fields and arrays. I was trying to figure out how to count how many entries in a table contain a certain value in that repeated column. And since the syntax [value] IN some_array is not valid, there is one extra that is needed.
Suppose we have some data around freemium podcast platform. In this platform users can pay for an upgraded service, or listen for free.</description></item><item><title>Blog Setup With Hugo and Github Pages</title><link>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-05-blog-setup-hugo-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 21:54:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwymak.github.io/tech/2021-11-05-blog-setup-hugo-github-pages/</guid><description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to revamp my blog, and rather than going with medium, thought that it&amp;rsquo;s a bit nicer to use my own site as the content remains under my control and I can use markdown. Github has a good set of documentation on setting up a github page, but as I am using Hugo as the static site generator, there are a few extra things I need to add. These are the steps I used to get it all up and running.</description></item></channel></rss>